

Will Sherman

Experience Designer

0438 804 826
will@willjsherman.com
willjsherman.com
LinkedIn

Before designing a solution, you must first understand the problem, the stakeholders involved, the users and how they can all benefit from your solution. Passionately collaborative, I work with stakeholders to create solutions that balance perfection with pragmatism. I always look for data, I always do my research and I love making things better!

Experience

Techniques & skills

- 15+ years Stakeholder management: Presentations, reporting, relationship building
- 5+ years Stakeholder collaboration: Workshops, design thinking, feedback collection
- 5+ years UX research: Competitive analysis, journey mapping, data analysis
- 5+ years UX design: Sitemaps, wireflows, wireframes, mock-ups, prototypes
- 5+ years Interviewing: Plans, scripts, interviews, synthesis, analysis
- 5+ years Discovery: Creating user types/personas, generating & understanding needs
- 3+ years UI design: Asset design, colour theory, design system creation
- 2+ years Information architecture analysis, restructuring & testing
- 2+ years Accessibility and inclusive design
- 2+ years CX (Customer Experience) and blue sky feature design

Tools

- 3+ years: Design & prototyping: Adobe XD, Sketch, Abstract, Invision
- 1+ years: Data analysis & optimisation: CrazyEgg, Google Analytics
- 1+ years: Online workshopping: Miro, MS Whiteboard
- 1+ years: Dev tool familiarity: HTML, CSS, Sass, Quasar, Bootstrap (I'm NOT a dev)
- 5+ years: Graphic design: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop
- 3+ years: Online collaboration tools: Teams, Trello, Jira, Confluence, Azure DevOps
- Comfortable working in Agile / Scrum or waterfall (or blends thereof) environments

Industries

- 5+ years: Tech
- 1+ years: Defence, AFP, Home Affairs
- 1+ year: Enterprise Services Management industry (ServiceNow)
- 1+ year: Financial/Banking
- 1+ year: Government contracting
- 1+ years: GIS industry

Soft skills and qualities

- Strong empathy, backed-up with a wealth of life experience
- Extremely team-oriented and collaborative
- Friendly & easy to work with
- Humble and always open to feedback and ideas
- Flexible, adaptable & passionately pragmatic

Career

Synth Technologies: Senior UX Designer

July 2021 - Sept 2022, BRISBANE, QLD (remote)

TASKS: UX design, UI design, stakeholder engagement & collaboration

DESCRIPTION: I brought UX and UI to this small but rapidly growing Defence project- crafting plans, documentation and

assets to support this groundbreaking GIS software project

Credit Union Australia/Great Southern Bank: Senior UX Designer

August 2019 - April 2021, BRISBANE, QLD (mostly remote)

TASKS: UX design, some CX, some UI design, lots of research, analysis, testing

DESCRIPTION: I worked on website sections, features for the online banking and mobile banking platforms, performed

research and concept development with the CX team

Freelance: Experience Designer

NOVEMBER 2018 - August 2019, BRISBANE, QLD (on-site and remote)

TASKS: Experience design, UX design, Interaction Design, UI design, research, analysis, testing

DESCRIPTION: I performed a range of contracts as an independent freelance experience designer, performing a variety

of tasks within that realm with a variety of clients

Enable Professional Services: UX Specialist

AUGUST 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018, BRISBANE, QLD (on-site and remote)

TASKS: "UX Team of One": research, experience design, usability testing, CX analysis, UI design

DESCRIPTION: Mainly service portal projects in the enterprise services management industry - designing experiences for requesters and fulfillers, interaction design, usability testing

8 Arms Consulting: UX Consultant

MAY 2015 - AUGUST 2017, BRISBANE, QLD (on-site and remote)

TASKS: "UX Team of One": research, UX design, a little SD, a little CX design, UI design, testing

DESCRIPTION: I frequently worked cross-functionally, taking on problems that required creative problem-solving across departments and between business and client stakeholders

Daddy time: I took two years off to stay at home and take care of our two little boys. It was by far the hardest thing I've ever done in my entire life.

Wavemaker Group: Principal Marketing Consultant

MAY 2008 - FEBRUARY 2013, AUSTIN, TX (on-site and remote)

TASKS: Marketing strategy, Service design, UX design, a little CX design, visual design, events

DESCRIPTION: My work spanned a wide range of roles, contracts and industries - from craft beer to energy efficiency to

large-scale promotions and events

Education & certifications

NV1 security clearance

December 2021

The Iron Yard Coding Bootcamp / UX/UI Certificate

May 2015 - July 2015, AUSTIN, TX

University of Texas / BA Communication

SEPTEMBER 1993 - MAY 1998, AUSTIN, TX

University of East Anglia / Communication Studies

JUNE 1997 - DECEMBER 1997, NORWICH, ENGLAND